Tisch Library Records UA137
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Undergraduate Research Award, 2012 -- 2015; UA137.008; 18 Digital Object(s)
  - The Levant unveiled: Western travelers' reports on Ottoman female bathing culture, 2014; UA137.008.033.00012; Weinstein, Molly L.; Beginning in the mid-sixteenth century, western European travelers began venturing to the Ottoman Empire on a more frequent basis. This increase in Oriental travel yielded a new collection of travel narratives. A topic of particular interest in the western travelogues was the Ottoman institution of the hammam, or bathhouse, and the ostensibly lewd behavior that took place within. Specifically, the behavior of Turkish females within the enclave of their all-female bathing quarters sparked the interest and imagination of early travelers. This study surveys the various references to Turkish female bathing culture within western European travel narratives from the mid sixteenth to mid eighteenth-century. It contends that the conjectural claims of female lesbian bathhouse activity made by early male writers reflected a strategic maneuver to reaffirm Christian values and to frame its adversary, Islam, as an amoral and illegitimate alternative; to assert western ethical and, consequentially, political superiority; and to expose domestic readers to a titillating and otherwise taboo subject matter while reinforcing their confidence in the propriety of their own sexual and cultural values and mores. Later reports on bathing culture by the British Ambassadress Lady Mary Wortley Montagu contradicted the earlier accounts, yet were equally deliberate. Montagu's carefully crafted image of a modest and dignified female bathing scene fed into her broader idealized claims of Turkish female sovereignty, exposing an oft-overlooked strain of western gender insecurity and female malcontent. In both cases, the collective preoccupation with Turkish bathing ritual and sexual activity is emblematic of a western fascination with the alien and of a willingness to contort and exploit the foreign to satisfy domestically rooted demands for cultural reinforcement and political justification.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Travelers' writings, European.; Travelers--Turkey--Attitudes.; Bathing Customs--Turkey.; Women--Turkey--Social life and customs.; Turkey--History--Ottoman Empire, 1288-1918--Social life and customs.
  - Swinging before Śiva: renunciation, colonialism and a Bengali ritual, 2014; UA137.008.033.00013; De, Aniket
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award, Department of Religion.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Rites and ceremonies--India--Bengal.; Renunciation (Philosophy); Imperialism--Social aspects--India--Bengal--History.; India--Religion--19th century.
  - The Greatest Casualty, 2015; UA137.008.033.00014; Bell, Julia
    Young soldiers are returning home from the Afghanistan and Iraq wars with a wide variety of health problems, both mental and physical. The Veteran Affairs health care system is unfortunately not nearly as accessible or reliable for veterans as it needs to be. The government needs to make mental health counseling mandatory for returning soldiers in order to ensure veterans' long term well-beings after they return home from service. It is the United States government's responsibility to take care of those who have honorably served this country, and it is crucial that these protectors are not forgotten.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Tufts University. Department of English.; Veterans--Medical care--United States.; United States.--Veterans Administration.
  - Dump the Dump!, 2015; UA137.008.033.00015; Weber, Alizee
    This project investigates the effect on the environment and the local communities of the renovation of the 91st Street Marine Transfer Station (MTS) in the residential areas of the Upper East Side, Yorkville, and East Harlem in the City of New York. The goal of this paper is to gain an understanding of the complex concepts and challenges that underlie this burning issue to evaluate potential solutions. To do so, the discussion focuses on topics such as environmental justice and discrimination, zoning laws, pollution and industrial hazards, waste responsibility, waste reduction and recycling, and clean energy. While this paper addresses the concerns of nonprofit organizations, it strives to maintain an objective point of view on the subject at hand by contrasting those views with that of government officials, and urban and environmental planning scholars.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Tufts University. Department of English.; Refuse and refuse disposal--New York (State)--New York.; Environmental justice--New York (State)--New York.
  - A'isha: The Evolution of Her Interpretation, 2015; UA137.008.033.00016; Eisenberg, Katherine A.
    This paper uses A'isha bint Abi Bakr as a lens through which to examine the nature of the debate over early Islamic female figures as it has evolved from the medieval period. It deals primarily with the depiction of A'isha's figure as it intersects with the concepts of female seclusion and Islamic feminism.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Tufts University. Department of History.; Muslim women.; Muḥammad, Prophet, 632--Family.; ʻĀʼishah, approximately 614-678.
  - The Demand for Rail Transit: an Analysis of Boston's MBTA, 2015; UA137.008.033.00017; Conwell, Lucas J.
    This paper estimates a derived demand model at the station level for the MBTA heavy and light rail system, making use of demographic, transit service-related, and built environment variables to run a simultaneous equations regression. I confirm the hypotheses that average speed of the rail line, median income, percentage of residents under age 35, and WalkScore positively impact transit ridership at the station level, but find no evidence that headway is negatively correlated with demand. Ideally, my results should provide Massachusetts policymakers and practitioners in the field of transportation planning with a clearer picture of the driving forces behind rail transit demand.
    Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Tufts University. Department of Economics.; Urban transportation--Massachusetts--Planning.; Local transit--Massachusetts--Planning.; Econometric models.; Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority.
  - From Sengoku to Sexy: How Japanese Culture is Preserved in Anime, 2015; UA137.008.033.00018; Richieri, Julia L.
    As time moves on, technology inevitably advances. With this comes new ways of recording, understanding, and transforming the past. In Japan, folktales and traditional stories are a huge part of culture. These stories were passed down orally at first, then on paper handscrolls. When these scrolls became obsolete, the stories moved to woodblock prints, and then to children's books in the more modern era. Now, as printed text loses its appeal to children, how are traditional stories and legends to be preserved? Strange though it may seem, anime just might hold the answers. If we consider the ways in which Japanese animation preserves history, albeit adjusted to be understood by a modern viewer, popular television shows and videogames become more than simply Saturday morning cartoons.
    Japan--Social life and customs.; Tisch Library Undergraduate Research Award.; Tufts University. Department of German, Russian and Asian Languages and Literatures.; Animation (Cinematography)--Japan.
- Additional accessions, UA137.009
  - Michalek office files, 1995 -- 2011; UA137-001 (Box 1)
  - Michalek office files, 1995 -- 2011; UA137-002 (Box 2)
  - Michalek office files and Author Talk publicity, 1995 -- 2012; UA137-003 (Box Shared 147)
  - Michalek electronic files, 2000 -- 2011; UA137-004
  - Possible Ritter materials from the Music Library, 1875 -- 1943; UA137-005 (Box 3)
  - Office files, 1990 -- 2000; UA137-006 (Box 4)
    Added one file from Laura Walters re: Gilmont donation, summer 2012.
  - Tisch Turns Ten DVD, 2006; UA137-007 (Box 5)
    3 copies
  - Subject files from Charlotte Keys, 1981 -- 2007; UA137-008 (Box 6)
  - Reference and instruction statistics, 1999 -- 2006; UA137-009
  - Floor plans, 1970 -- 1995; UA137-010 (Box 7)
  - Lincoln exhibit materials, 2005; UA137-011
  - Oversized Posters, 2012; UA137-012 (Box 8)
  - Engineering reference brochure, 2003; UA137-014
  - Instructional statistics, 2011 -- 2012; UA137-015
  - Podcasts and transcripts, 2007 -- 2009; UA137-016
    Podcasts created by library staff from 2007 - 2009, about the library and topics pertaining to reading, writing, and research
  - Tisch Library renovation documentation, 1994; UA137-017 (Box 9)
  - Regina Raboin office files, 1998-2014, UA137-018 (Box 10)
    Office files, circa 1998-2014, generated during Regina's multiple roles at Tisch, including Microforms and Current Periodicals Collection Coordinator, Data Management Services Coordinator, and Science Reference Librarian.
  - U-Matic tapes of class lectures and student productions, 1975 -- 1985; UA137-019 (Box 11)
  - Library Committee, 1927 -- 1992; UA137-020 (Box 12)
    Tufts Library background documents for Library Committee, 1992; copies of documents of predecessor committees, circa 1927-1969
  - Wessell Library slides, circa 1977 -- 1978; UA137.009.021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12)
    Slides of Wessell Library (which would later become Tisch Library), including exterior and interior spaces, such as stacks and offices. Approximately 80 images.
    Transferred by Laura Wood, 2016, accession UA-2017-018.
- 2019 accessions, 1980 -- 2010; UA137.010; 4.8 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Transferred by Tisch Library, 2019, accession UA-2019-056.
  This series contains administrative records from Tisch Library, largely created by the Library Director's office, including meeting agendas and minutes, planning documents, committee and task force documentation, user surveys, events and publicity materials, building and construction documentation, and accreditation information.
  - TEC Net, 1996; UA137.010.036.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Tufts University Library Systems Office, 1995 -- 1997; UA137.010.036.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - University Library Council, 1997 -- 1999; UA137.010.036.00003; 3 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 3-5)
  - Policy Memos, 1996 -- 1998; UA137.010.036.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - NELINET, 2003 -- 2009; UA137.010.036.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Mission Statement Arts and Sciences Library, 1991; UA137.010.036.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Board Of Overseers University Libraries/Arts and Sciences Library, 1997; UA137.010.036.00009; 2 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
  - Depository Libraries, 1980 -- 1991; UA137.010.036.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Planning Documents, 2003 -- 2004; UA137.010.036.00012; 2 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
  - Tufts Planning, 1990 -- 1991; UA137.010.036.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Library Updates, 1994 -- 1996; UA137.010.036.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Librarians Guide, 2001 -- 2003; UA137.010.036.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Kresgge Foundation Proposal, 1993; UA137.010.036.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Higher Education Initiative, 1998; UA137.010.036.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Staff Travel Committee, 1992 -- 1996; UA137.010.036.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Staff Development Committee, 1996 -- 1997; UA137.010.036.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Staff Recognition Award Committee, 1992; UA137.010.036.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - New Staff Orientation Comm, 1992; UA137.010.036.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Serials Conversion Task Force, 1993; UA137.010.036.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Self-Study Report, 1997; UA137.010.036.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Archives, 1996; UA137.010.036.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Committee Listings, 1998 -- 2002; UA137.010.036.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - EUST Continued, 2004 -- 2007; UA137.010.036.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - SCT, 2002 -- 2005; UA137.010.036.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - FRT 2004, 2003 -- 2004; UA137.010.036.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Tisch Teams, 2005 -- 2006; UA137.010.036.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - ARL, 1983 -- 2000; UA137.010.037.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Boston Library Consortium, 1988 -- 2004; UA137.010.037.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Fact Book, 1994 -- 1998; UA137.010.037.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - NACUBO Benchmarking, 1992; UA137.010.037.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Gale Research, 1994; UA137.010.037.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - HEDS Senior Survey, 1991 -- 1997; UA137.010.037.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - IPEDS, 1994 -- 1998; UA137.010.037.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - NELINET Task Force on Outsourcing, 1997; UA137.010.037.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Tisch Library User Survey, 1990 -- 1999; UA137.010.037.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - User Survey 2000, 1999 -- 2000; UA137.010.037.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - User Survey 2001, 2001 -- 2002; UA137.010.037.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - ACRL Statistics, 1989 -- 1998; UA137.010.037.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - User Survey, 1993 -- 1994; UA137.010.037.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - User Survey, 1992 -- 1993; UA137.010.037.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - User Survey, 1994 -- 1995; UA137.010.037.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - User Survey, 1991 -- 1992; UA137.010.037.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - User Survey 1996, 1995 -- 1996; UA137.010.037.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - User Survey 1997, 1997 -- 1999; UA137.010.037.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Web Usability Survey 1999, UA137.010.037.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - No User Survey FY98, 1998 -- 2001; UA137.010.037.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - FY99 User Survey, 1999; UA137.010.037.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Assorted Papers, 2003 -- 2005; UA137.010.037.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Tower Café Student Survey, 2004 -- 2005; UA137.010.037.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - The Tower Donor Prospects, 2003; UA137.010.037.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - The Tower Publicity/Logo, 2004; UA137.010.037.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Spirit Coupon, 2004; UA137.010.037.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Ribbon Cutting, 2004; UA137.010.037.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Other Library Coffeeshops, 2003 -- 2005; UA137.010.037.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Café Planning, 2003; UA137.010.037.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Milles Jumbo Fountain, 1995; UA137.010.037.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Komidor Garden Dedication, 2002; UA137.010.037.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Uhrig, 2002; UA137.010.037.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Mural Information, 1983 -- 1994; UA137.010.037.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Art Mural - YenShang Yuan, 1983 -- 2010; UA137.010.037.00034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Art - Exterior, 1996; UA137.010.037.00035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Art Competition (lobby), 1996 -- 2004; UA137.010.037.00036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Forever Free, 2002 -- 2007; UA137.010.037.00037; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Publicity, 1994 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Music Lib, 1999 -- 2007; UA137.010.038.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Archives Move & Shelving, 1996; UA137.010.038.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Level G Renovation, 2003; UA137.010.038.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1995 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Dedication 1996, 1994 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Floorplans and Furniture, 1994 -- 1995; UA137.010.038.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Donors to Tisch Library, 1996; UA137.010.038.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - SBRA, 1993; UA137.010.038.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Alex's Place, 2006 -- 2009; UA137.010.038.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Shelving, 1991 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - FLC FY97/98, 1994 -- 2002; UA137.010.038.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Job Meetings 7/1994-7/1995, 1994 -- 1995; UA137.010.038.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Construction Costs, 1988 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Construction Phasing, 1994 -- 1995; UA137.010.038.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Design Develop., 1992 -- 1994; UA137.010.038.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Proposal for Architectural Services for Design and Construciton of Wessell Arts and Sciences Library Tufts University, 1992; UA137.010.038.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Library Expansion Docs, 1992 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Development/Dedication, 1994 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Publicity/PR, 1994 -- 1996; UA137.010.038.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Assorted Docs - Library, 1987 -- 1997; UA137.010.038.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Videocassette: Yuan Yunsheng - Portrait of an Artist - Dru Burtz/Laura Batistich, 1983 -- 2010; UA137.010.039.00001; 1 Audiovisual Object(s) (Box 39)
  - Binder: Forever Free: Abraham Lincoln's Journey to Emancipation, 2002 -- 2006; UA137.010.039.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Postcards and Holiday Cards, 2008; UA137.010.039.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Suggestion Board Policy (Revised 1997) with suggestions from patrons, 1997 -- 2004; UA137.010.039.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Boston Library Consortium, 2000; UA137.010.039.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - BLC Task Force, 2001 -- 2001; UA137.010.039.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Tisch Library Annual Reports, 2005 -- 2010; UA137.010.039.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Accreditation Report - NEASC, 1997; UA137.010.039.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 8)
- 2020 accessions, 1956 -- 2005; UA137.011; 6.1 Linear Feet 3 record cartons, 1 oversize box, 1 photograph box
  The photographs in this series have been maintained in their original order.
  This series contains photographs, scrapbooks, and clippings related to Tisch Library. The majority of the photographs document staff and library events.
  - Photograph albums and scrapbooks, 1956 -- 2005; UA137.000940 (Box 40)
  - Event and building photographs, 1993 -- 2003; UA137.000941 (Box 41)
  - Scrapbooks, 1963 -- 1991; UA137.000942 (Box 42)
  - Event photographs, 2000 -- 2002; UA137.001135 (Box 44)
    Printed photographs and digital photographs on CD-Rs, primarily of library events.
  - Event photographs, 2003 -- 2010; UA137.001136 (Box 45)
    Digital photographs on CD-Rs, primarily of library events.
- 2021 accessions, circa 1993 -- 2016; UA137.001137; 2 Digital Object(s); 302 Megabytes; 1 Linear Feet
  Transferred by Tisch Library, 2021, accession UA-2022-007 and UA-2022-027.
  This series contains administrative subject files, including advancement, budget, construction, event, strategic planning, Poetry Walk, and Tisch Library construction files. Budget records include collections budget updates, Berger Fund and Advisory Board records, materials budget information, and endowment information. This series also contains author talk photographs and videos and luncheon event programs.
  - Administrative subject files, circa 1993 -- 2016; UA137.001138 (Box 46)
  - Anne Sauer author talk, 2002; UA137.001139; 98.15 Megabytes
    Author talk with Anne Sauer organized by the Friends of Tufts Libraries on the photo history of Tufts University.
  - Rocky Carzo author talk, 2006; UA137.001140; 204.49 Megabytes
    Author talk with Rocky Carzo, athletic director emeritus at Tufts and author of "Jumbo Foot Prints: A History of Tufts Athletics, 1852-1999." The event was organized by the Friends of Tufts Libraries as part of "Tisch Turns Ten" events.